嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
你们在干什么  我们想填完字谜再去睡觉
What are you guys doing up? We wanted to finish the crossword before bed.
你知道三个字  也是红色的一种
Do you know a six-letter word for "red"?
深红色
Dark-red.
应该不是  不过你待会可以玩连连看
I think that's wrong, but there's a connect-the-dots in here for you later.
嘿  赭红色呢
Hey, how, uh, about maroon?
没错  你好聪明
Yes! You are so smart! Ha-ha-ha.
哇
Aw.
你们好可爱啊
You guys are so cute.
我知道
I know.
好  明早见
All right. I'll see you in the morning.
好
Okay.
我最喜欢跟你玩填字谜了
You know, I love doing crossword puzzles with you, honey.
我也是
Oh, me too.
赶快填完去睡觉  好的
Now, let's finish this and go to bed. Okay.
只剩一个
There's only one left.
叁个字的动物  不是小狗  是
Three-letter word. Not dog, but...
猫咪
Cat.
没错
Yes. Ha.
你好聪明
You are so smart!
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
老友记  第五季  第16集  警察来了
Friends  S05E16  The One With A Cop
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
还差小费
We still need a tip.
好  等等
All right. Hold on.
有了
I got it.
5分钱
Nickel.
还差多少  2块钱
How much more do we need? A couple of bucks.
10分钱
Okay, dime.
你们继续聊  我会多花一点时间
You guys should probably keep talking. This could take a while.
等等  你们看
Wait, lookit!
哇啊
Whoa!
天哪  这是警徽
Oh, my God. This is a police badge!
真酷  但警察来这里干嘛  这里又不卖甜甜圈
Oh that's so cool! Why would a cop come in here though? They don't serve donuts. Ha.
你能不能重来一次
Y'know what actually, could you discover the badge again?
我可以说个更好笑的
I think I can come up with something better than that.
菲比   一定有人正在找那个警徽
Phoebe, I bet somebody's missing that badge.
没错  我应该送回去  知道吗  我去了警察局
Yeah, I should take it back. Ooh,  but you know what? While I'm at the police station, ...
还可以看看十大通缉犯名单
...I could check their Ten Most Wanted list.
因为我朋友丽西一直是排名第11大  今年也许会走运
because my friend Fritzi's been Number 11 forever. so this could be her year!
嘿  大家好  嘿  乔伊
Hey, you guys. Hey, Joey.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
那是我的衣服吗
Hey. That uh, that my sweatshirt?
对  对不起  我会冷  冷了就借来穿了
Yes, it is. I'm sorry. I borrowed it. I was cold. I hope it's okay.
没关系吧  你要穿  应该穿
It's just that, uh, if you wear someone's sweatshirt...
你男朋友的衣服  才对吧
...shouldn't it be your boyfriend's?
我不是你的男朋友
And I'm not him.
对不起  我现在就还你
I'm sorry. I'll give it back.
不  不  不要
No, no. No.
上面会沾满你的味道
I mean it's gonna be all smelling like Monica!
你是说我很臭吗
Are you saying I smell bad?
不  不是
No. No.
你有一股青草香
You smell like a meadow.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他是怎么了
What's with him?
乔伊上次去青草地  他妈妈被猎人射杀了
Oh, y'know what? The last time Joey went to a meadow, his mother was shot by a hunter.
我还是不确定
Yeah, I still don't know.
抱歉  我想买到理想的沙发  我希望这张沙发能让人觉得
I'm sorry I just wanna make sure that I bought the right couch. I need a couch that says:
"小朋友  欢迎"  同时也能让人觉得
"Kids welcome here," but that also says
"来我身边吧"
"Come here to me."
什么  你对小朋友说那种话
What? You say that to kids?
不  不  不是
No, no, no.
"来我身边吧"  是对小姐们说的
The "Come here to me" is, you know, for the ladies.
罗斯  这是张好沙发  但不是神奇沙发
Ross, honey, it's a nice couch, not a magic couch.
对啊  你的选择很正确
Well, you picked a great couch.
是吗  是的
Yeah? Yeah.
没错  请在这里签个名  没问题
Yeah. Could you just sign right here please? Oh, sure.
没问题  这是
Oh, what's, heh--?
运费几乎跟沙发价格一样贵
The delivery charge is almost as much as the couch!
真是太扯了  他家离这里才三条街
That's ridiculous. He lives three blocks away.
算了  我自己搬好了  谢谢
You know what? I'll take it myself. Thank you.
瑞秋  来吧  好
All right, Rash, come on. Let's go.
好
Yeah.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
才三条街  又不是很重  抬抬看  快  快
Come on. It's only three blocks. Uh, it's not very heavy. Try it. Come on! Come on!
喔  我行嘛  行
Oh, I can do it. Yeah.
你们会很喜欢这张沙发的
You two will really enjoy that couch.
我们  不是一对
We're, uh, not together.
哇啊  哦  哦
Oh, okay. Yeah. Ha-ha-ha.
难怪我看着怪怪的
Something didn't quite add up there.
罗斯
Ross.
你这话是什么意思  罗斯
What's that supposed to mean? Ross.
你  她
Well, you. Her. Heh.
她很...你知道
I mean, she's very...
你知道
...you know.
And you're, like...
而你却
"NQU know'?
虽然与你无关  但我们确实交往过
Not that it's any of your business, but we did go out.
真的  你们两个
Really? You two?
对  瑞秋
Yeah. Rash'?
我现在不想说这个  我抬着一张很重的沙发
Come on, I don't really want to be doing this right now. I am carrying a very heavy couch.
那你就赶快告诉他啊
Then tell him quickly.
好  我们交往过
Fine. We went out.
不只交往过
Not only did we go out...
我们还做过298次
...we did it 298 times!
罗斯
Ross.
我实在
Oh, WV"
你居然在计算  真没用
Ugh, you kept count? You are such a loser!
再没用你也做了298次
A loser you did it with 298 times!
哇  啊
Oh. Oh!
这位小姐  怎么了  你不能在树上熄香烟
Excuse me, ma'am. You can't put your cigarette out on a tree.
没事  我可以  很方便的
Yeah, I can. It worked well.
你不该这么做  别再这么做了
But you shouldn't. So don't ever do that again.
我不会了  抽下一根烟之前不会
I won't till I have my next cigarette.
站住
Hold it!
纽约警察  别动
NYPD. Freeze, punk!
什么
What?
没错  你被活逮了
That's right. You are so busted.
把她带走
Book 'em.
你在跟谁说话  别挣扎了  红发女
Who are you talking to? Save it, red!
不想在笼子里过夜  就跟那颗树道歉
Unless you want to spend the night in the slammer, you apologize to the tree.
我才不跟一颗树道歉呢
I am not going to apologize to a tree.
赶快道歉  否则我要叫人了
You apologize to the tree right now, or I am calling for backup.
来人啊  来人啊
Backup! Backup!
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry! Sorry!
好  别来了  别来了
Okay, cancel backup! Cancel backup!
好吧
Okay.
罗斯  你不是说有电梯嘛
Ross, didn't you say that there was an elevator in here?
我是有说  但其实没有  来吧
Uhh, yes I did but there isn't. Okay, here we go.
好  往左
Okay, go left.
左  左
Left. Left.
好  拜托  这儿没有左可以往左了
Okay, you know what? There is no more left, left!
好  抬高到你的头上
Oh okay, y'know lift it straight up over your head!
抬高到你的头上  你行的
Straight up over your head. You can do it!
你行的
You can do it!
好  没问题吧  很好
Okay. You got it? Yeah.
Go, go. Good, good.
没问题吧  没问题吧  没问..
You got it, right? You got it, right? You got--
你觉得放在那里好看吗
Any chance you think the couch looks good there?
这家伙还在碎碎念
...so this guy was all...
我就说  "重案组  布非"
And I'm all, "Buffay! Homicide!"
真是太帅了
It was just so cool! Ha-ha-ha.
菲比  你应该拿去还的
Phoebe, you were supposed to take that back.
我知道  但行善的感觉好棒
I know, but I'm having so much fun doing good deeds.
但假扮警察很严重  你会被逮捕的
Okay, but impersonating a police officer is a serious thing. You can get arrested.
你现在就会被逮捕
You could get arrested right now!
好吧  我得拿去还了  我被权力冲昏头了
All right, yeah, I'd better take it back. I'm totally drunk with power.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
嗨  乔伊
Hi, Joe.
我不知道你们会在
Yeah. I didn't know you guys were gonna be here.
乔伊  你尝尝看  什么  为什么
Hey Joey, do me a favor, sweetie. Taste this. What? Why?
你是怎么了  没事啊
What is going on with you? Nothing.
拜托  你一整天都怪怪的
Oh, come on! You've been acting strange all day.
好吧  是有一件事  我
All right. There is something. I, uh...
我做了一个梦
I kind of had a dream.
但我不想谈
But I don't want to talk about it.
马丁路德金恩也这么说  还得了
Oh, whoa. What if Martin Luther King had said that?
我有一个梦
I kind of have a dream.
但是我不想谈
I don't want to talk about it.
跟摩妮卡有关
Look, it involved Monica.
你梦到我正在交往的女孩  真是酷啊
You had a dream about a girl I'm seeing? Oh, that is so cool.
我不知梦见他的女朋友多少次
I can't tell you how many times I dreamt about a girl he was seeing.
总之  我们在谈你的梦  我爱你  你的梦
Anyway, we were talking about your dream. I love you. Your dream?
放心  没有任何性意味  自从发现你们的事
Don't worry, there wasn't any sex in it. I haven't dreamt about her like that...
我就不对她做那种梦了
...since I found out about you two-ish.
那你梦到什么
What was the dream about?
好吧
Well, okay.
你是我的女朋友  我们在填字谜
You were my girlfriend. We were doing the crossword puzzle.
就像你们昨晚那样
Y'know like you guys were doing last night.
就这样  我爱上摩妮卡了 我会搬走
So that's it. I'm in love with Monica and I'll be moving out.
乔伊  等等  那并不代表你爱我
Wait, Joey, come on. That doesn't mean that you're in love with me.
不是吗
It doesn't?
它可能有很多涵义  例如
It could mean anything. Like, uh...
你突然眼红我成为这里的猛男
...all of a sudden you're jealous that I've become the apartment stud.
这个  听起来比较像你的梦
That kinda sounds like your dream, dude.
或是你看到我和钱德在一起  很亲密
Or it could mean you saw Chandler and me together, and we y'know were being close and stuff...
你也想跟别人拥有这种亲密关系
...and then you just want to have that with someone too.
我在梦里的确很享受那种亲密
In the dream I did enjoy the closeness.
好  听着
Okay, look.
你爱上摩妮卡了吗
Are you attracted to Monica?
就是现在  此时此刻  爱上她了吗
Right here, right now, are you attracted to her?
其实没有  这就对了
Not really. There you have it!
当然啊  我穿得这么随便
Heh. Well, sure! I'm just wearing sweats!
但那是好事
But that's good!
你不是爱我  你只是想交个女朋友
You're not in love with me. because you just want a girlfriend!
不  我觉得不是交女朋友的问题
No, I don't think it's just about getting a girlfriend.
对  我可以找个女朋友
Yeah, Y'know? I mean, I could get a girlfriend.
对  我们可以坐在那里填字谜
Yeah, we could sit in the chair and do crossword puzzles.
但我们会拥有你们那种亲密感觉吗
But y'know are we ever gonna have y'know the closeness like you guys have?
摩妮卡和我是从朋友做起的  也许关键在这里
Monica and I were friends before we started dating. Maybe that's it.
先做朋友
Friends first?
有意思
That's interesting.
你们都事后当朋友  没有  也从来没有过
You become friends after? No, never done that either.
嘿  你们有量尺吗
Um, do you guys have a tape measure?
有  在我房里
Oh, yeah. It's actually in my bedroom.
没错
That's right.
乔伊  怎么了
What's up, Joey?
你好吗
How you doing?
抱歉  这是你的车吗  对
Excuse me. Is this your car? Yeah.
停在这里不太好  你挡住出入口了
Well, I don't think it's nice of you to park here. You're blocking the entrance.
放心  没关系的
Don't worry about it. It's not a problem.
我觉得有关系  你就有关系  因为我是条子
It's a problem for me, which means it's a problem for you because I'm a cop.
我也是
So am I.
完了
Oh, no.
好  你是条子  可以任意停车
Oh, okay. so you're a cop which means you can park anywhere,
因为我也是条子
'cause I know that 'cause I'm a cop too.
好  继续努力  收到
So, all right, keep up the good work. Ten-four.
等一下  你是哪个分局的
Hey, wait a second! So wait, what precinct are you with?
我在57分局
I'm with the, um, the 57th.
我认识你们重案组一位刑警  我在风化组
I know a guy in Homicide up there. I'm in Vice.
事实上  我正在卧底  我是妓女
Yeah, In fact, I'm undercover right now. I'm a whore.
风化组还有谁
Who else is in Vice up there?
你认识
Um, do you know, um...
西波威兹吗
...Sipowitz?
西波威兹  不  应该不认识
Sipowitz? No, I don't think so.
对  西波威兹  大块头  有点秃
Yeah. Sipowitz. Yeah. Big guy, kind of bald.
我不认识他
I don't know him.
不要打给他  他不在  他出去了
Don't try to call him or anything. Because he's not there. He's out.
他的拍档  刚死了
His, um, partnerjust died.
帮我跟西波威兹致意
Tell Sipowitz I'm real sorry for his loss.
我会的  保重
I sure will. Take care.
对了  我相信西波威兹不会有事的
Hey, by the way, I'm sure Sipowitz is gonna be all right.
听说那个新来的小伙子很不错
I heard that kid from Silver Spoons is really good.
你在哪里找到我的警徽的
And where did you find my badge?
嘿  乔伊  你能不能帮我和罗斯搬沙发
Hey, Joey, would you mind giving me and Ross a hand moving his couch?
我很想  但我要去上表演课  但你知道
Aw, I'd love to but I got acting class. But you know what?
我可以为了你跷课的
I guess I could blow that off for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
瑞秋  我问你件事  我刚在对面跟摩妮卡和钱德聊天
Uh, hey, Rach let me ask you something.Uh, I was just over there talking to Monica and Chandler,
他们可真亲密
Boy, they are really tight.
是啊
I know.
那种关系实在很不错
Yeah that's not such a bad situation they got going over there.
我也想自己弄一段
I'm thinking of getting me one of those.
你想说什么  乔伊
What's up, Joe?
我觉得他们感觉会那么好
The reason I think Monica and Chandler are so great...
是因为他们是先做朋友
...is because they were friends first, you know?
于是我问自己  谁是我朋友  你和菲比
So I asked myself, who are my friends? You and Phoebe.
而我先遇见你  所以
I saw you first, so...
你在说什么  我是说也许你我可以更进一步
What are you saying? I'm saying maybe you and I crank it up a notch.
乔伊
You know, honey, um...
你先过见我
..as, uh, flattered as I am...
真令我受宠若惊
...that you saw me first...
但我不觉得我们应该更进一步
...uhh, I just, I-I don't think we should be cranking anything up.
我会对你很好
I'll treat you real nice.
对  你知道吗
Yeah. Well, you know, um...
我觉得先做朋友再交往  是一个很好的想法
Listen, I think it's a great idea to become friends with someone before you date.
但你应该先去认识一个人  跟她做朋友
But I think the way you do it is you meet someone, become their friend...
建立基础  再约她出去
...build a foundation, then ask them out on a date.
别对现有的朋友下手
Don't hit on your existing friends.
那不是要等很久了
Won't that take longer?
没错  没错
Yeah. Yeah.
但是一旦得到了
Oh, but once you find it...
真的很值得
...it's so worth the wait.
这样
Yeah.
我懂  我懂
I understand. I understand.
很好
Good.
天啊  如果先遇见菲比就好了
Man, I wish I saw Phoebe first.
来我身边吧
Come here to me.
不  不  你来我身边
No, no. You come here to me.
嘿  罗斯
Hey, Ross.
我带援军来了  太好了  是乔伊吗
Ahem, I brought reinforcements. Oh, great! You brought Joey?
只比他差点
Well, I brought the next best thing. Heh.
嘿
Hey-
钱德  你带钱德来  只差一点的应该是摩妮卡
Chandler?!  You brought Chandler? The next best thing would be Monica!
我应该感觉不爽了  但摩妮卡真的壮得可怕
Y'know, I would be offended, but Monica is freakishly strong...
看  我画了一张搬运草图
Look, I drew a sketch of how we'll do it.
好  瑞秋  这是你
Okay ,Rach, that's you.
这是沙发
That's the couch.
那是什么
Oh, what's that?
那是我
Oh, that's me.
你把自己看得很雄壮喔
You certainly think a lot of yourself.
不  那是我的手臂
No. That's my arm.
喔  我还以为你那么喜欢你的新沙发
Oh, I see. I thought you just really, really liked your new couch.
总之听我的指示
Just follow my lead.
好
0key.
钱德  来吧
Come on, Chandler.
好  开始了
All right. Okay.
开始了
Here we go.
可以了吗  可以
All right. Ready?
转  好
Turn! Okay.
转
Turn!
应该是转不动了  我觉得挤不上去
I don't think we can turn anymore! I don't think it'll fit!
当然可以  快抬起来  抬起来  抬起来
Yeah, it will. Come on! Up, up, up!
抬起来  很好
UP! Yes!
很好  中心点
Here we go! Pivot!
中心点
Pivot!
闭嘴  闭嘴  闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
好  我看是上不来了
I don't think it's gonna pivot anymore.
是吗
You think?
好吧  搬下去再来一次
All right, let's, uh, bring it back down and try again.
现在真的卡死了
I think it's really stuck now.
想不到居然没成功  就是啊  我也没想到
I can't believe that didn't work. I know. Me neither.
你都画了图了
I mean, you had a sketch.
你说那个 "中心点"是什么意思
What did you mean when you said "pivot"?
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
怎么样  有交到新朋友吗
How's it going? Did you make any new friends?
有  我认识了一个女人
Yeah. I met this woman.
嘿  哇  哇
Hey. Whoa, whoa.
她怎么样
What's she like?
她的
Uh, well, she's...
床上功夫很棒
...really good in bed.
乔伊  你不是要先当朋友嘛
Joey, I thought you were going to try to be friends first.
都是你的错  什么  为什么啊
Well look, hey, it's all your fault. What? Why?
因为你给的不是忠告  是搭讪词
Well because you didn't give me advice. No! You gave me a pickup line.
我一说要 "建立基础  先当朋友"
As soon as I told her I wanted to y'know, "build a foundation and be friends first."
她突然就...与我本身无关  觉得我难以抗拒
I suddenly, through no fault of my own, I became irresistible to her!
她的室友也是
And her roommate!
那亲密关系呢
What about the "closeness"?
谁还管亲密啊  我们玩三P啊
Closeness, schmosness! There was three of us, for crying out loud!
谁要吃彼萨
All right! Hey, Who wants pizza?
我要  我要  我要
I do! I do! I do!
赞  这是我在二楼捡到的
Oh, great! Can you believe I found this on the second floor?
哪位  纽约警察
Who is it? NYPD.
天啊  天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God.
等下  警察先生
Uh, just a minute, officer!
我要找菲比布非  完了  是他  是那个警察
I'm looking for Phoebe Buff ay. My God, it's him! It's that cop!
他居然找到我了  天哪  菲比  你会去坐牢吗
I can't believe he found me! Oh my God, Phoebe,Are you going to go to jail?
我死也会拖你们下水的
Well, If I'm going down, you guys are going down with me.
窝藏逃犯  起码要关1到3年
Harboring a fugitive? That's one-to-three years minimum.
钱德  祝你好运
Good luck, Chandler.
好  你可以逮捕我  但你抓不到我的把柄
Okay, you can arrest me, Fine. but you'll never make it stick and you know it.
但我别无选择  这是我的职责所在  你了解吧
Yeah, but I kinda don't have a choice, it's my job. You understand, right?
当然  只要你了解我  会找我的律师来
Yeah, as long as you understand that I'm gonna call my lawyer.
他会让你在庭上像个猪头  猪头
And once he puts you on the stand, he's gonna make you look like a fool! Like a fool!
我不喜欢当猪头
I don't like looking foolish.
这样吧  也许我今天不抓你  就说我来了 但你不在
Y'know what? Maybe, uh, I don't arrest you today. Maybe I came by and you weren't here.
我不在就太好了
I would love it if I weren't here!
既然你今晚不会入狱  我能不能
Okay, so since umm, you're not going to jail tonight, I was wondering if you'd, um...
请你和我去晚餐
...like to go to dinner with me?
我  对
Me? Yeah.
自从你对我亮警徽  我就对你念念不忘
Ever since you flashed my badge at me, I kind of can't stop thinking about you.
你是我见过的最美的假卧底妓女
You're the prettiest fake undercover whore I've ever seen.
漂亮
Nice.
我想不到你会来  约我出去
Wow, I didn't see that coming. You're asking me out.
我可以表现得更好  但这些人一直盯着我看
Yeah, I could've done it better, but these people keep staring at me.
好  我愿意跟你出去吃饭  警察先生
Um, yeah, I'd like to go out with you, officer.
盖瑞  盖瑞
Gary. Gary.
那就这么说定了  好
Okay, so it's a date. Yeah.
不过我一定要问  你是怎么找到我的
Yeah! So--ooh, I gotta ask you, though. How did you know where to find me?
我的警徽上都是你的指纹  所以我上电脑查询
Your fingerprints were all over my badge so I ran them through the computer.
这是你最后登记的住址  所以我就来看看
This was listed as your last known address so I checked it out.
好厉害
Oh, impressive.
没有你厉害  我看过你的纪录  你干过不少怪事
Not as impressive as you. I looked at your record and you've done some weird stuff.
吃饭时再说
We'll talk at dinner.
好
0key.
我两个小时后来接你
So I'll come by in a couple hours and pick you up?
好  我好兴奋
All right, I can't wait. Okay.
放心  我不会只带你吃甜甜圈
Don't worry, I won't just take you out for doughnuts.
他有枪
He has a gun!
我要退这张沙发  我不满意
I'd like to return this couch. I'm not satisfied with it.
你要退这张沙发
You want to return this couch?
它断成两半了
It's cut in half.
我就是这个意思  是你把它切成两半的
That's what I'm telling you. Did you out this couch in half?
这张沙发被切成两半
This couch is cut in half!
我要换一张没有被切成两半的
I would like to exchange it for one that is not cut in half.
你是说它送过去就这样了
You're telling me this couch was delivered to you like this?
我很讲道理
Look, I'm a reasonable man.
我愿意接受换购抵用券
I will accept store credit.
我给你4元的换购抵用券
I'll give you store credit in the amount of $4.
我接受
I Will take it.